Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adopted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
I can cut a thousand strands of hair
but I cannot sever the tangled threads of my mind.
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Bowing with my hands clasped, I give away my throne.
Lowering my head, devoted to the beauty by my side.
The wheel of fate turns, granting blessings or misfortune.
Will it be destiny’s trial or reward?
Heaven’s will cannot be known,
weaving together weals and woes.
For lovers caught in eternal time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
He didn't come.
My Lady, are you talking about Noble Prince Guo?
I'm so foolish.
Why would a Noble Prince like him come out
on such a rainy day?
He must be reciting poems now in his estate.
He spoke in jest
but I took him seriously.
Perhaps he was being sincere
but the rain made it inconvenient to come to the palace.
We should go back, My Lady.
Don't get wet.
Let's go.
Has the harem become more peaceful lately?
Everything is well.
That's good.
I'm no longer young, or capable
of managing palace affairs.
The Emperor oversees the imperial court
and you must manage the harem like a household.
You should put your whole heart into it.
I will, Imperial Mother.
Your Majesty, I came to check earlier.
No one was here.
With such heavy rain,
I can understand why she didn't come.
Nothing matters as much as Your Majesty's health.
Please go back. The wind is getting stronger.
Your Majesty has been working late these days.
You already had a cough.
I will be punished if Your Majesty catches a cold.
Your Majesty, please go.
"Over the majestic mountain, rises a moon so tiny."
"The moon, so tiny, is silvery and shiny."
"I pine for the man traveling distantly."
"Each day apart makes my heart sink heavily."
What are you reciting, My Lady?
Nothing.
The zither unveils the heart of the performer.
My Lady, you have something on your mind
and cannot let it go.
He is a Noble Prince, and you are a concubine.
Forgive me, My Lady, but you shouldn't
have gone there today.
I know.
I'm just a secluded Attendant, without favor.
I haven't even seen the Emperor's face...
But I still won't have any relations with Noble Prince Guo.
You are His Majesty's concubine, My Lady.
And he is His Majesty's brother.
If rumors are whispered in the wind,
he won't be affected, but you will suffer, My Lady.
I know.
Sourire.
You came right after the rain stopped
even though the road must be slippery.
His Majesty got sick, but I don't need to attend to him.
If I didn't come here, what would I do?
Meizhuang is there.
It must be hard for her
to serve alongside Consort Fleur.
Have some tea.
All right.
It's so strange that His Majesty fell ill.
How could he have gotten a cold?
Everyone can feel under the weather.
Your Majesty, the medicine is ready.
Bring it to me.
Let me serve it to Your Majesty.
You were here the whole night.
You should go get some rest.
I'm so used to serving Your Majesty
I couldn't rest assured if it was anyone else.
Meizhuang is a reliable person.
She is, but she is new to the harem.
She can be clumsy and careless sometimes.
My Lady, Lunar is here.
Peace to Attendant Sourire.
The Household Department has obtained some
spring textiles. Please join Lady Shen in selecting them.
Why does she have spare time today?
I thought she was tending to His Majesty.
Is His Majesty well now?
Yes. Lady Shen hasn't had to go for the last two nights.
The spring scenery has arrived.
I regret to be remiss about it.
It was precisely because Your Majesty indulged
in springtime beauty
that you caught a cold in the Imperial Garden.
The Empress Dowager was talking about spring flowers
in the Imperial Garden.
I was hoping to be a devoted son
by personally picking some beautiful flowers.
Who could have known that I'd catch a cold
from the dampness of the spring rain?
We know Your Majesty was being a devoted son,
but the ignorant might say that
the wicked garden flowers captured your heart.
Not as wicked as the green-eyed monster.
You don't read much, but you're quick to argue.
All right, you've been tired lately.
Go back and have some rest.
Yes.
As soon as Your Majesty came back from court,
I asked for medicine to be prepared.
Please take it before you read the memorandums.
Su Peisheng.
Your Majesty.
Go on a walk with me.
Wait, get me my casual clothing.
It's her again.
Who is it on the swing?
Why are you not coming to greet My Lady?
Come here! I'm talking to you!
My Lady is Attendant Sourire of the Palace of Pearl Jade.
She doesn't dress like an Attendant.
Is there an Attendant Sourire in the harem?
I've never heard of her.
My Lady, there is indeed an Attendant in
the Palace of Pearl Jade.
But she was sick and put into a quarantine.
Greetings, Attendant Sourire.
I'm Companion Yu.
Greetings, Companion Yu.
How come you fancy going on a walk out here?
I've been busy serving His Majesty.
How could I be as leisurely as you?
But I will offer my advice to you, Attendant Sourire.
Since you're sick, you should stay in your palace.
Otherwise, you'll spread your bad luck to the palace.
Thank you for the reminder.
But there's something I need to tell you as well.
Is that so? I'd very much like to hear it.
I've heard that His Majesty likes well-mannered concubines.
But you did not bow to me properly when you saw me.
You must be unfamiliar with the etiquette in the palace.
How about my maid shows you how to do it properly?
You can watch and learn.
Yes.
Companion Yu, please watch.
Companion Yu bows before Attendant Sourire.
Peace and grace to Attendant Sourire.
Other concubines have praised you for being a fast learner.
I believe you can follow Vermillion's demonstration
and do it properly now.
You're just an Attendant, with no favor.
You want me to bow before you like that?
How dare you?
My Lady, Attendant Sourire does rank above you ...
My Lady ...
Do you not know who your mistress is?
Attendant Sourire, do you really believe that your status
in the palace is determined by your rank?
You'll rank higher if His Majesty favors you.
Otherwise, you're just a lowly servant,
regardless of your title.
Besides,
you are merely one rank above me.
How dare you tell me what to do?
What if I told you what to do?
What if I made you bow to Attendant Sourire?
Peace to Your Majesty.
What has brought Your Majesty here?
And what brought you here?
I heard that Your Majesty has been
coming to the garden a lot recently.
I thought the garden must be beautiful,
so I came here for a walk.
You are not being honest.
I was simply hoping to keep Your Majesty company.
How come you know so much about my whereabouts?
My Lady... My Lady...
I bow before Your Majesty.
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
Peace and Grace to Your Majesty.
That day
I didn't mean to break my promise.
Although I've been ill,
my heart has been with you at this place.
Did you come here and wait for me afterwards?
Rise.
Hold on to your mistress. She's delicate.
My Lady.
You still haven't learned your lesson!
It seems that punishment
by the Empress Dowager was too lenient.
Your Majesty, I admit my fault.
My mind was clouded
and I offended Attendant Sourire.
I will... I will beg Attendant Sourire for her forgiveness.
Please spare me this time, Your Majesty!
I am unworthy of your forgiveness for my grave offense.
Please remember that we both serve His Majesty,
and seek His Majesty's leniency for me.
Your Majesty.
"A fault confessed is half-redressed."
I believe Companion Yu is sincerely addressing her mistake.
I hope Your Majesty can show mercy.
Since Attendant Sourire interceded for you,
I shall not slight her feelings.
But I detest your repeated misconduct.
Su Peisheng.
Your Majesty.
Yu is demoted to Escort.
She will move out of the Palace of Accumulated Purity,
to a place I can't see.
Yes.
Your Majesty...
You were saying that Attendant Sourire
was only one rank above you.
I hereby promote Attendant Sourire to Noble Lady.
Your Majesty, I'm afraid
it's inappropriate to promote Attendant Sourire
since she hasn't served you...
You've become so masterful in your service.
You dare to question my decrees?
I would not dare.
I will announce Your Majesty's edict right away.
Are you so overjoyed
that you've forgotten to thank me?
Your Majesty,
I have made no contribution
to either state affairs or family expansion.
I do not deserve Your Majesty's heavenly grace.
You deserve it if I say so.
Rise.
Don't tire yourself out by kneeling so much.
Escort Yu, please take your leave.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
Are you scared?
There's sweat on your hands. Are you nervous?
You are the Emperor.
You weren't afraid of me before.
You were fearless.
I didn't know you were the Emperor, but now I do.
The Son of Heaven carries authority
and inspires awe in my humble being.
Awe leads to inhibition,
and that will turn us into monarch and subject.
I didn't mean to let you down that day, in the heavy rain.
I was a few steps away from the garden
but the Empress Dowager summoned me.
I hurried back to the garden
only to miss your beautiful presence.
Instead, I had a cold for days.
Has Your Majesty recovered?
I am talking to you here - as right as rain.
It was foolish of me.
Because you care.
Later, I thought
you couldn't have come.
You were recuperating and it was raining badly.
In fact, I came to the garden as promised.
Really?
Were you caught in the rain?
Did that affect your health?
I thank Your Majesty for asking.
I am standing here - as right as rain.
That's good.
I was concerned about your health
since you have been unwell.
But why... would Your Majesty deceive me?
It was not deception.
I simply did not want you
to be afraid, or submissive, or fawning,
because of who I was.
I do not wish to end up alone in the palace,
with no one to confide in.
I barely know Your Majesty.
I dare not see myself as Your Majesty's confidante.
I appreciate you for who you are.
I wouldn't have taken our meeting
so seriously if you were like the other concubines.
I'm dull-witted for not discovering your identity.
How could you have known if I deliberately hid it from you?
But my seventeeth brother is bitter about this.
He's often been confined in my palace lately.
Your Majesty planned it thoughtfully.
I wouldn't have known.
Your hands are cold.
Is it because you've been standing in the wind?
I'm not cold.
You've been outside for quite a while.
I'll walk you back.
No, you must be tired.
I'll carry you in my arms.
I would not dare.
Why not?
Your Majesty will become the subject of gossip.
I'm taking care of a lady I'm fond of.
Let them gossip all they want.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade🫣
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Peace to Your Majesty.
Peace to Noble Lady Sourire.
You're already well-informed.
The Palace of Pearl Jade is honored
by Your Majesty's grace to My Lady.
We all are grateful to Your Majesty.
All rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
You are clever and articulate.
What's your name?
Your Majesty, my name is Vermilion.
I am My Lady's dowry maid.
Like master, like servant.
I thank Your Majesty.
My arms are sore.
Does Your Majesty think I am too heavy?
Not at all.
I was afraid I would hurt you if I held too tightly
or you'd fall if I loosened my grip.
My arms were in a conundrum, and ended up feeling sore.
Your Majesty is teasing me.
Is Noble Lady Sourire being attended to by
such a small number of servants?
Yes.
I need a quiet environment.
There's no need for me to have many servants.
But this is unacceptable.
Who are the head eunuch and head maid?
Your Majesty, my name is Cui Jinxi.
I am the head maid of the Palace of Pearl Jade.
There is currently no head eunuch in this palace.
The former head eunuch Kang Luhai was sent to
work for Concubine Beauté two months ago.
That's all right.
But you need a head eunuch in your palace.
I will ask the Household Department
to select a few skilled eunuchs for you tomorrow.
You will choose one as your head eunuch.
I appreciate Your Majesty's offering.
But there's no need to go through so much trouble.
I think Xiao-Yunzi is quite competent.
He can take on this role and gain some experience.
I thank Your Majesty.
I thank My Lady.
I will do everything I can to serve My Lady.
Of course, if that's what you wish.
The new eunuchs wouldn't know you as well.
Lady Sourire appreciates your work.
You must do your job well.
Yes, Your Majesty.
You've just been promoted.
You should have more servants.
I'll ask the Household Department to bring you some good ones.
I thank Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, Mr. Zhang Tingyu requests an audience.
I see.
Rest well and take care.
I'll come and see you in two days.
I bid Your Majesty goodbye.
You know my rules.
I know that Your Majesty doesn't like to be disturbed
(Peace)
when you practice calligraphy.
But I wanted to report that
Companion Yu has been punished and demoted to Escort.
By His Majesty?
Exactly.
That was expected, but sooner than I imagined.
Make sure that she's behaving herself.
Yes.
Yu is shallow. She doesn't deserve to serve His Majesty.
And yet she didn't care about proper demeanor.
What happened?
She offended Noble Lady Sourire of the Palace of Pearl Jade.
She became a Noble Lady so soon.
His Majesty must be fond of her.
It seems so. But it's against the rules of the palace to promote
a concubine before she serves His Majesty.
The rules of the palace were created by our forefathers.
Those ancestors were the Sons of Heaven
and the current Emperor is also a Son of Heaven.
"A dragon does not belong to the pond."
Her ascendancy was only a matter of time.
- Goodbye, Mr Lu.
- Thank you for coming, sir.
Peace to Noble Lady Sourire.
His Majesty ordered me to send gifts here
as soon as he got back.
Thank you, sir.
It is an honor to be of your service.
Here is a pair of gold lace sachets,
a pair of blue cloisonné bracelets,
a box of gold-inlaid jeweled hairpins,
two boxes of palace flower hairpins,
a pearl curtain,
sixteen pieces of satin in various colors,
and a special gift from His Majesty.
Please see it yourself, My Lady.
I thank His Majesty.
His Majesty wishes for the flute to
brighten your days as you make a recovery.
He hopes it can bring a smile to your face.
It's not appropriate to visit and thank His Majesty while I'm sick.
I hope you can convey my gratitude for me, sir.
My pleasure.
His Majesty knows you shouldn't be disturbed.
You may close your gate to visitors
other than His Majesty and the doctors.
I hope Madam Cui can see to it.
Certainly, it was very thoughtful of His Majesty.
Allow me to take my leave, My Lady.
Our storeroom is filled with gifts from other palaces.
- Huan.
- Meizhuang.
This day has finally come.
Peace to Lady Sourire.
What's this about? We are sisters.
Meizhuang was overjoyed over your good news
and dragged me all the way here.
But I have to stay clear-headed not to break any rules.
She's right, let's go talk inside.
Let's go.
We don't need to be attended to.
You may all stay outside.
How did you rise and become Noble Lady Sourire without notice?
I don't have the faintest clue.
Not a single whisper was caught in the wind.
I never meant to hide anything.
I met His Majesty by chance in the Imperial Garden.
As the old saying goes,
"The quiet bird amazes the world when she sings."
That is your story.
I thought it was a rumor when my maids told me about it.
We were not convinced until
Mr. Su came to announce the edict.
We came immediately to congratulate you.
But countless pairs of eyes will be watching you now.
- You have to be careful.
- I understand.
But His Majesty holds you in high esteem.
He made an exception and promoted you before you served him.
You don't need to worry now that you're favored.
It does worry me to be the exception.
Having too much favor is not a good thing.
With the Emperor's favor, they can't do anything to you.
I heard His Majesty reprimanded and punished Yu
because she offended you.
With her as an example,
no one will dare to provoke you.
Companion Yu was at fault,
but I'm afraid that the same fate will befall me one day.
If I make a mistake, it would implicate my entire family.
There's no escape now that you're the centre of attention.
But having His Majety's favor shining on you
is better than being alone.
Don't worry, Sourire.
Your only concern is to nourish your health
and truly live as a Noble Lady.
Lingrong is right.
As long as we join hands,
no one can defeat us in the palace.
What kind of hell is this place?
Why wasn't it even cleaned?
My Lady, you are not living in the Palace of Purity anymore.
You would have been sent to the Cold Palace
if it weren't for His Majesty's feelings for you.
You wouldn't have your own room and maid there.
My Lady, you can clean it yourself and live with it.
Sir, please let me see His Majesty.
His Majesty will forgive me.
I'm flattered, My Lady.
But we all serve under Mr. Xia [Xiao-Xiazi].
Since you despise us for being eunuchs,
we are unworthy of serving you.
Don't be angry, My Lady.
How dare you!
Peace and grace to Your Highness.
I brought the stipend for Your Highness's palace.
It looks heavier than what we had last month.
The stipend is the same, but we must show our piety
in return for Your Highness's good graces.
You have a grateful heart. Rise.
I thank Your Highness.
Now that His Majesty has a new Noble Lady,
the Household Department will be busy
taking care of that.
Not at all. I thank Your Highness for your caring words.
The work for a Noble Lady doesn't take much time.
Lady Sourire was unheard of and unnoticed.
I'm sure she's suffered some trouble from your department.
But now she's in favor,
can you keep on scraping the bare minimum?
Isn't that good?
If His Majesty listens to her pillow-side whispers,
I cannot help you with that.
Please pity us, Your Highness.
What can I do for you?
You manage the Household Department.
Be careful in selecting the servants you send to her.
My Lady, Consort Fleur had desserts sent to you.
Please have some.
Her Highness's palace makes better pastries
than the Imperial Kitchen.
They are never easily sent as a gift.
You can go now.
The dessert looks ten times nicer
than what we receive from the Imperial Kitchen.
Then you should have some, My Lady.
But when I look at it, I'm reminded of
how Consort Fleur punished Xia with "Three Yards of Red."
Jinxi, I'm really worried.
The wind in the harem changes with every blink of an eye.
Responding with fear is not enough.
But all changes are of the same essence.
His Majesty's favor is the most important.
Too much favor is frowned upon by the harem;
Too little favor is trodden upon by anyone.
My Lady, you must know that
whether you're in favor or not,
rivalries are never far away from you.
For example, you are close with Lady Shen and Companion An,
and you will be seen as your own faction.
Meizhuang and I grew up together.
We will look after each other with one heart and mind.
I didn't mean your sisterly bond is a bad thing.
But speaking of "one heart and mind",
that's not only true for the harem,
but also for the harem and the court.
You can see that from Consort Fleur's example.
Favor in harem is inextricably linked
to the shifting tides at court.
I only wish for my family to have a peaceful life,
and for His Majesty to treat me with a kind heart.
I'm glad you think that way, My Lady.
Since you have entered the palace as a concubine,
you are no longer the same as the ordinary girls outside.
You don't always have control over life and death.
Fortunately, I can see His Majesty is very fond of you.
And you are fond of him too.
I was going to make three wishes
in the Garden of Leaning Plums.
But I didn't have time to say the last one.
I'm listening with my whole heart, My Lady.
My third wish:
I wish to grow gray and old with one who loves me wholeheartedly.
But the one who has my heart
is the last person who can love me with his whole heart.
But you can wish for the next best thing.
Instead of his whole heart,
you can hope for his earnest heart.
My Lady, your health has generally recovered.
But I can still explain to His Majesty
that your condition is still not favorable for serving him.
We've been slowing down my recovery with herbs for a long time.
If His Majesty sends other doctors to treat me,
will they be able to find out?
What will happen if they do?
Last time, we both had the choice to use herbs.
This time, I have to make a full recovery behind closed doors.
You have no option, and neither do I.
I'll obey your orders, My Lady.
I would be walking on thin ice without your help, Dr. Wen.
I will always keep my promise to protect you.
Thank you.
Please restore me to my health,
but not so fast.
A month would be ideal.
I will reduce the dosage and add nourishing herbs.
That will do.
Thank you, Dr. Wen.
Goodbye, Dr. Wen.
Peace to Noble Lady Sourire.
We have diligently selected the best maids and eunuchs
to serve you, My Lady.
Please rise, sir.
I trust your choices, Mr Huang.
Otherwise, if anything goes wrong,
I'll have to send for your service.
Yes, yes.
Jinxi, help them orient themselves.
Follow me.
My Lady, I beg your forgiveness for my idiocy.
I was occupied with some trivial matters
and asked Xiao-Luzi to take care of
the painting request from your palace.
But this fool was careless and dared to forget about it.
I've brought the offender here today, My Lady,
hoping that he can receive your punishment and pardon.
We dare not punish your staff, Mr. Huang.
They will talk about our palace
and their words can choke us.
Vermilion, mind your manners.
It's not like that, Miss.
It's all my fault for not properly disciplining my staff.
It's not your fault, sir.
Your department manages thousands of strands and
loose ends, intertwined with people's affairs.
Some oversight is inevitable.
Why should that deserve any punishment?
Thank you for your caring words, My Lady.
We will do more than our best
to serve you in the future.
We brought you a new table, My Lady.
I hope you can pardon its crudeness.
Thank you for remembering my request.
Xiao-Yunzi, put it away.
My Lady, I shall take my leave
if you do not have other requests.
- Take care, sir.
- Thank you, My Lady.
Go, go.
Why were you so imprudent with your words?
Huang Guiquan turns his ship whenever the wind changes direction.
He embezzled your supplies before,
and has now sent a scapegoat to butter you up.
You can keep that to yourself and be vigilant.
If you offend him openly, others will say
we have become arrogant because of our status.
Oh... I won't do it again.
I know you were doing it for me.
But we are not fighting this battle with our tongues.
Everyone in the palace bends with the wind.
Not just Huang Guiquan.
I'm sorry, My Lady.
It's all right. Your words cautioned him.
Tell the servants not to talk about it.
My Lady, Huang Guiquan is a relative of Consort Fleur.
I know. I'll tell Jinxi and Xiao-Yunzi
to watch the newcomers with extra vigilance.
in case anyone lays a finger on us.
They will only do menial tasks.
You will keep tending to my personal tasks.
Yes, My Lady.
Peace to Lady Sourire.
His Majesty will be here after lunch.
Please be prepared.
Thank you, sir.
You may take your time and get changed, My Lady.
His Majesty is coming.
My Lady, you should wear a bright-colored dress.
Why? This looks fine.
It is nice, but it looks a bit too simple.
What's wrong with being a little homey?
Peace and grace to Your Majesty.
It's windy today. Let's go inside quickly.
"A lotus has surfaced from the clear water;
her beauty is naturally unadorned.”
My Lady Sourire is surely one of a kind.
It's because Your Majesty appreciates
my plainness, like the catkins of willow.
You are dressed elegantly,
and your maids are also exquisite.
It feels like a refreshing breeze to the mind.
This is my dowry maid, Jade.
Jade? No wonder she's dressed in jade.
Jade.
His Majesty might not like more followers.
Let's stay outside.
Just as well.
While many other maids are wearing the same color,
you were the only one noticed by His Majesty.
I thought His Majesty would notice Vermilion first
for her red dress.
Vermilion is beautiful too,
but you bear resemblance to My Lady.
That's why you caught His Majesty's attention.
Is that so?
Your Majesty, I made some tea for you.
I don't know if it suits Your Majesty's taste.
You made it yourself. I appreciate your thoughtfulness.
The tea smells so fragrant.
It smells fresh and goes deep into the lungs.
It's winter tea from Yuezhou.
You added plum flowers and pine leaves.
What else is in it?
Your Majesty has expert taste.
I named the tea "the three winter friends".
It's brewed with plum flowers, pine needles, and bamboo leaves.
The water is from the dewdrops on lotus leaves
collected last summer.
"Tea clears a foggy mind."
After drinking your tea,
I realize the truth behind what the ancients said.
I'm flattered.
I received two jars of the tea last year.
I brought one to the palace
and stored the water under the pear tree in the yard.
We started making the tea two days ago.
How do you like living in this palace?
It seems to be a bit remote.
I thank Your Majesty for asking.
I enjoy living here. It's quiet and peaceful.
It is peaceful, but a bit far
from the Hall of Mental Cultivation.
But my heart isn't hindered by the distance.
As long as our hearts are close.
Yes, our hearts are always close.
You look much healthier now.
You'll be fully recovered soon.
I have a weak constitution. It's not a serious illness.
Blessed with Your Majesty's care and concern,
I will be well soon.
I can't take my eyes away from you when you're being shy.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Support our volunteers: magpiebridgebrigade.cn
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Phoenix Taking Flight
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
The dreams I dimly recall;
The past I hardly remember,
amidst the autumn moons and the spring flowers.
Like the moon's reflection on water
or flowers seen through mist - floating and drifting.
The joyous sounds you brought;
The silence you left;
Changing faster than clouds can turn to rain.
Our minds resonated;
Our hearts beat in unison;
But we lost what we once possessed.
A poem to converse;
A melody to accompany;
A heart to bind to mine.
I hoped for endless longing and eternal promise,
but I’m left with only the flute and the zither.
With affection, I pleased;
With my heart, I committed;
With my arms, I embraced.
I desired to be remembered;
Desired to be cherished;
Why am I only hated and deceived?
My wish ran against my will.
Behold the mockery of destiny and the game of fate.
My unwavering love is gone
like flowers swept away in the wind.
Praying for a bright moon;
Praying for a rising sun;
Dreaming to bask in the spring breezes.
But the unsparing northern winds carry snow and rain
to destroy the aspirations of the plum tree.
A phoenix about to take flight rustles its wings
but the arc of its flight is unseen.
The phoenix tree sways in the wind,
shedding memories in the whispers of the falling leaves.